SHAH MUHAMMAD **BABAR**



www.shahmbabar.com

hi@shahmbabar.com

□

(+92) 322 4589 426

Lahore, Pakistan





SUMMARY

Shah Muhammad Babar is a digital product expert focusing on branding, product design, typography, and design generalism. He is a specialist to works creatively from scratch. He has worked with numerous companies worldwide, solving their problems and catching opportunities with his unique and creative ideas, creating the next generation of digital brands and experiences. He has the ability to making the balance between great design and functional development. He can collaborate network of designers, strategists, directors, and developers to execute projects and provide valuable perspectives on work.

Shah Muhammad Babar holds solid visual communication, product development, and design generalist background. He worked on numerous worldwide renowned projects, Branding and Promotionals Campaign for "Digital Immortal Ecosystem" at United Nations. He worked on the Branding and Marketing Campaign of APEC (Asia Pacific Economic Corridor) 2018 at Papua New Guinea (PNG). He worked on the Brand Identity of Suponic (Multinational Blockchain Group) and appreciated the work by Richard Kim (BMW i8, i3 Chief Designer)

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Graphic Design University of Management and Technology (UMT), Lahore, Pakistan
- Faculty of Sciences (F.Sc.) pre-engineering BISE Lahore, Pakistan
- Certification of Motion Graphics Masterclass Udemy online course
- Ceritfication of User Experience Essential Udemy online course
- Ceritfication of Fundamental of Typography Udemy online course

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- UI/UX Design .
- Product Design
- Packaging Design .
- Design Generalism
 - Design Direction
 - Typography •
- Product Photography .
- Media and Communications .
- Marketing and Digital Platforms .
 - Project Management •
 - Visual Communication -
- Branding and Public Relations .

TOOLS & SOFTWARES

- Adobe Creative Suite .
 - Figma .
 - Adobe XD .
 - Wix .
 - Miro .
 - Invision •
 - Font Creator .
 - MS Office .

WORK EXPERIENCE

Suponic

Jan 2018 - Present

Creative Design Head/Product Designer

Suponic is a global creative technology firm with a key focusing on providing a user-friendly innovative solution coupled with exceptional customer service. I am working as a Creative Design Head handling all the design work of Suponic Group, from Brand Identity to Product Design and Execution.

- · Responsible for managing all corporate designs for the Company, including media, visual communications (internal and external), product designing, case studies, competitive analysis, wireframing, customer stories, branding, and advertising matters for the organization
- · Design Managing various international events and conferences
- Developing vital products for users, media and digital strategies
- · Drafting/designing presentations, whitepaper & profiles.
- · Managing corporate branding and visual reputational matters

Baroog Studios

Creative Lead/ Design Generalist

Barooq Studios is a team of multidisciplinary digital product experts focusing on branding, UI/UX design, mobile and web development, SEO, product photography & videography. It is a digital agency having full-stack specialists to work creatively from scratch.

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

- · Responsible for all visual communications, media, and marketing related tasks for Studio
- Managed marketing events include digital social media campaigns, product photography, corporate videography, and corporate branding.
- Managed, produced, and developed management solution products (UX/UI)

Icustom Boxes

Head of Creative Department

Feb 2014 - Dec 2015

ICustomBoxes is Canada's trusted packaging company. I worked as a Creative Head of the Design Department. My responsibilities were to give directions to the design team and handle all the creative work-related product/packaging designing and branding.

- · Overall management of daily activities of visual designers with a team of 15+ designers.
- · Preparation (and presentation) of monthly design management and reports for the Board.
- · Rebranding of the ICB logo and refreshed the company image.
- · Developed and implemented key features and marketing strategies.
- · Internationally recognized packaging company with 100+ clients
- · Developed and maintained interactive relationships with clients.
- Design presentation of packaging on various international panels and forums on Digital and Print Media.

Bozail

Senior Visual Designer

July 2012 - November 2013

Bozail Studio is a progressive website development, graphic design, and creative solutions firm based in Northeastern Pennsylvania. Art Street's mission is to provide innovative solutions for clients relying on technology to grow their business.

- · Overall responsibility for all creative visual affairs and daily operations of the company.
- Direct management of Client Design Services, Facilities and give them support related to promotional graphics and visual communication.
- ${\boldsymbol \cdot}$ Handled all programming requirements with the collaboration of developers and designers
- · Management of junior designers to complete and direct their projects.
- Responsible for maintaining quality management of visual graphics by balancing aesthetics and visuals of designs.
- · Grew the business and increased revenues by providing high-quality work for happy clients.

Jolta Technologies

UI/UX Designer

Dec 2010 - June 2012

Jolta Technologies Limited was established in Hong Kong in 2009, a Development and Manufacturing facility for iPhone, iPad, Windows Phone, and Android Smartphone Games and Applications. I worked as a Game User Interface/User Experience Designer in the Lahore office. During my work experience, I learned about design principles that were related to game

- · Working closely with the design team to develop good quality games with good user experiences
- .• Overall responsibility of all User Interface design of games, from research to development, and testing and assuring the quality of graphics.
- Responsible for the acquisition of all content alignment, balancing, typography, and composition.
- Represented the games at IOS and Playstore platform to the audience worldwide with promotional graphics to grab the attention of users.
- · Collaborate with developers and team leaders to make sure the interaction and addiction of game.
- Game UI designs following the updating trends and art style.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Product Design and Development execution of Management Solution
- Product/Fashion Photography, Direction, Set creation and light sourcing.
- Brand Identity Creation with custom typeface design with mission, vision statement, portraying brand/company with it
- Packaging Design, Motion Graphics, 2d animation, Social media branding

ACHIEVEMENTS

Branding/Marketing Campaign at United Nations

Digital Immortal Ecosystem Branding/Marketing Campaign with promotional Visual Graphics UI/UX Products at United Nations

Branding / Marketing Campaign of Asia Pacific Economic Corridor (APEC)

Branding/Marketing Campaign of Asia Pacific Economic Corridor (APEC) 2018 held in Papua New Guinea with the presence of Prime Ministers, Presidents, Kings and Ministers.

Branding/Identity Creation of Suponic

Branding/Identity Creation of Suponic (multinational Blockchain group) by following the rules of design and company background appreciated by Richard Kim (BMW i8,i3 chief designer)